<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Erbil Aero Club</title>
    <link href="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club" />
    <updated>2019-08-29T23:15:50+03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Erbil Aero CLub</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club</id>

    <entry>
        <title>What is paragliding</title>
        <author>
            <name>Erbil Aero CLub</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/what-is-paragliding.html"/>
        <id>https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/what-is-paragliding.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-29T23:08:56+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    If you are unfamiliar with paragliding, then the first question you should want the answer to is, “What is paragliding?” To answer that question, paragliding is the activity of gliding through the air, only being attached to a parachute that resembles a canopy. Paragliders descend&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h3 id="mcetoc_1djffo1n40">If you are unfamiliar with paragliding, then the first question you should want the answer to is, “What is paragliding?” To answer that question, paragliding is the activity of gliding through the air, only being attached to a parachute that resembles a canopy. Paragliders descend from high altitudes, like mountains and cliffs.<span id="Wing" class="mw-headline"></span></h3>
<p> </p>
<h3 id="what-is-the-history-of-paragliding" class="b">What is the history of paragliding?</h3>
<p>You may be asking yourself why this is on the list. But, if you are serious about something, then you should know the history of it. Thus, you will have a better understanding of a topic, in this case, paragliding.<br>It all began in 1952 when Domina Jalbert modified basic gliding parachutes by adding controls and multi-cells to it, thus, there would be more of a lateral glide. Then, in 1961, Pierre Lemoigne designed a type of parachute, which would later lead to the design of the Para-Commander. The Para-Commander had a certain kind of design that allowed it to glide throughout the air and steered. Shortly after, in 1963, David Barish developed a single surfaced wing which was intended for recovery of NASA space capsules. The wing was tested on Hunter Mountain in New York, which shortly led Barish to promote the activity of slope soaring at ski resorts. In 1973, the word paragliding was finally coined when authors Patrick Gilligan and Bertrand Dubuis wrote the first flight manual, called, The Paragliding Manual. Finally, in 1978 friends Jean-Claude Betemps, Andre Bohn, and Gerard Bosson gained inspiration from The Paragliding Manual and decided to test it out. They launched from Pointe du Pertuiset, Mieussy, and flew 1000 meters. Ever since then, paragliding increasingly grew popular, and the equipment greatly developed.</p>
<h3 id="can-anybody-paraglide">Can anybody paraglide?</h3>
<p>Yes! Anybody can try paragliding. But while anyone can paraglide, you should be in physical shape.</p>
<h3 id="do-i-have-to-be-in-shape" class="b">Do I have to be in shape?</h3>
<p>Referring back to the last question, yes you should be in shape. Paragliding can be physically demanding in the sense that you should have good coordination and a lot of strength and stamina. You should also have a pretty good amount of flexibility. Along with being in physical shape, you should be in the best mental state. Mental ‘strength’ is important because you have to be on alert, and you should be able to make quick and reasonable decisions if certain conditions happen while in flight.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Gallery</title>
        <author>
            <name>Erbil Aero CLub</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/gallery.html"/>
        <id>https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/gallery.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-29T23:01:58+03:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="gallery"   >
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding-wallpapers-31286-4803337.jpg" ><img src="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding-wallpapers-31286-4803337-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="540"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding_2-wallpaper-3840x2400.jpg" ><img src="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding_2-wallpaper-3840x2400-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="450"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding-wallpapers-31286-1098650.jpg" ><img src="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding-wallpapers-31286-1098650-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="450"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding-wallpapers-31286-1745831.jpg" ><img src="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding-wallpapers-31286-1745831-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="480"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding-wallpapers-31286-4914666.jpg" ><img src="https://hozan7.github.io/erbil-aero-club/media/posts/1/gallery/paragliding-wallpapers-31286-4914666-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="405"></a></figure>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
